Joseph is a adventure, drama, tv movie film directed by Roger Young.
Joseph, favored son of Jacob and great-grandson of Abraham,
is sold into slavery by his jealous brothers.
Rising to become prime minister of Egypt.
Joseph governed the country during a seven year famine, during which his brothers visit
Egypt seeking grain, only to encounter their brother, presumed long dead.
Potifar, played by Ben Kingsley.
Josef, played by Paul Mercurio.
Lea, played by Dominique Sanda.
Potifars Frau, played by Lesley Ann Warren.
Jakob, played by Martin Landau.
Rahel, played by Alice Krige.
The Bible: Joseph is a 1995 German/Italian/American television
miniseries about the life of Joseph from the Old Testament.
It was filmed in Morocco and aired on TNT on April 16, 1995.
At the 47th Primetime Emmy Awards, from five nominations, Joseph won Outstanding
Miniseries, becoming the first show on a cable network to win in that Category.
The film explores themes of jealousy, christianity,
bible, ancient egypt, told in flashback.
The tone is emotional.